# Sofie Yates

323 Sixth Street, Boise, ID 97531 s.yates(g)myemail.com (876) 678-8765

Knowledgeable hydrogeo Legist with 7+ years' experience planning and carrying out water sampling and data analysis. Strong Leadership ability with a talent for effective task delegation and communicating complex procedures and plans. Superb attention to detail and ability to interrogate data and detect anomalies for further investigation.

## **Education**

# **Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science**

University of Idaho, Moscow, ID, September 2008 - June 2012

#### Master of Science in Environmental Science

University of Idaho, Moscow, ID, September 2012 - June 2014

# **Key Skills**

- ♦ Strategic planning
- \* Analysis and interpretation
- Data management
- Teamwork
- \* Leadership

# **Professional Experience**

#### Research Hydrogeologist

Boise State University, Boise, ID I August 2018 - Present

- « Plan and execute water sampling expeditions to remote locations and overcome accessibility issues, receiving a workplace commendation in 2020 for outstanding problem-solving skills
- Use a variety of equipment to measure water levels and flow rates and maintain precise records, achieving 99,8% accuracy over 2 years
- Supervise teams of up to 15 colleagues during borehole logging activities and communicate plans clearly, receiving 95% positive feedback for leadership skills
- Work collaboratively with the web design department to create educational online resources, increasing public engagement by 21% Last year

### Hydrogeologist

Suez-Na, Boise, ID | July 2014 - August 2018

- Analyzed geophysical Logs and presented findings clearly both verbally and in writing, receiving praise 4x during reviews for strong communication skills
- Planned and carried outfield investigations and recorded data using Microsoft Excel, exceeding 32% of delivery deadlines over 3 years
- Worked as a team with the geochemical department to recommend chemical maintenance strategies
- Maintained detailed and updated knowledge of local water rights legislation and emerging hydrogeological technologies